#### Contact

+919873774753 (Mobile) skumar@startup-monk.com

www.linkedin.com/in/siveshkumar (LinkedIn) startup-monk.com (Blog)

### Top Skills

Mentoring Entrepreneurship Start-ups

# Sivesh Kumar

Startup Guy | Help First Time founders & Early Stage Entrereuners to Succeed by Validation\Incubation\ Acceleration | Me Delhi

# Summary

Sivesh turns startups into profitable businesses, strategic consults for startups, and helps them use the available resources to generate traction, revenue, profitability and their overall bottom lines.

Sivesh recently founded "StartUp Monk", where he is trying to bring all stakeholders of the startup ecosystem on a single platform. He enjoys raising startups and moving forward to the next one and loves his dividends at the end of the year. Sivesh started with three failed startups before making the self-sustainable one. Which makes him an expert on what one shouldn't do while running a start-up.

Sivesh mentors early-stage startups with their strategy and business plans. He is part of the mentor pool of IIT K and IIM R. He is also part of jury member panel of some elite incubation and investor pitches. He believes that the path between idea and making startup sustainable is the toughest. Most startups fail during this stage under multiple numbers of pressures. He guides entrepreneurs on their startup and its market acceptability.

By education he is B.Sc. (Maths Honors) and MBA in Human resources (though he never worked as per his education). Sivesh is a certified photographer and a globetrotter (he enjoys exploring new places, people and culture on his trips).

He also Spoke at TEDx recently and is a Keynote speaker at various entrepreneurship events.

## Experience

StartUp Monk
Founder & CEO
December 2018 - Present (1 year 9 months)
New Delhi Area, India

StartUp Monk is a platform of the Startups, by the StartUps and for the StartUps. We are here to open doors of StartUp Ecosystem. The community aims to improve on facilitation of StartUp needs through right guidance, mentorship, and network.

Edudictive
Mentor and Director
July 2020 - Present (2 months)
New Delhi, Delhi, India

Edudictive is an ed-tech startup offering upskilling live courses for :

- 1. For School kids
- 2. For College students (project-based +placement focussed)
- 3. For aspiring entrepreneurs, the incubation programs with team formation support.

### Startup India

Mentor

January 2019 - Present (1 year 8 months)

New Delhi, Delhi, India

Helping entrepreneurs in converting their idea in the venture.

Entrepreneurship Cell, FMS Delhi Investor - Jury Member November 2019 - July 2020 (9 months) New Delhi Area, India

One of the Jury member of Investor Pitch session for Faculty of Management Studies, New Delhi

#### **Techstars**

Coach - Mentor

September 2019 - April 2020 (8 months)

Chandigarh Area, India

Techstars is a geographically distributed accelerator which provides both financial and advisory help to budding entrepreneurs. Focused exclusively on the early stage startup scene Techstars gives help to the freshest and most disruptive ideas. Mentors provide help, advice, counseling, and new perspectives to companies in the Techstars portfolio.

Skill Prodigy
Member Of The Board Of Advisors

#### May 2019 - February 2020 (10 months)

Melbourne, Australia

- Identifying, developing and directing the implementation of business strategy.
- Cultivating the company's reputation in the market & culture within.
- Involved in planning & organizing the organization's activities to achieve targets.

#### The Monk Store

Founder

June 2019 - January 2020 (8 months)

New Delhi Area, India

"The Monk Store" creates cool, kickass merchandise for hsutlers who never back down when the chips are down, and have a zen-like approach to creating the next big thing.

#### E-Cell IIT Roorkee

Jury Member - Pitch Session

September 2019 - November 2019 (3 months)

Roorkee, Uttrakhand

One of the Jury member of Startup Pitch session for Endeavour 2019, IIT Roorkee

#### The Capital Wizards

Strategic Advisor

September 2019 - October 2019 (2 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

Provide Mentorships to "Start-ups" in the portfolio of The Capital Wizards

To provide strategic advisory support with Startups validation review for investment.

Indian Institute of Foreign Trade

Investor / Jury Panel Member

August 2019 - August 2019 (1 month)

Kolkata Area, India

One of the Sharks in "Swimming with Sharks" - the Indian version of Swimming with the Sharks

International Management Institute - IMI Panel Member, E-Summit August 2019 - August 2019 (1 month) New Delhi, Delhi, India

Part of the panel for Entrepreneurship Summit for the discussion over "EVOLUTION OF THE REVOLUTION: INGREDIENTS TO A SUSTAINABLE STARTUP AND ITS ECOSYSTEM."

Ramanujan College, Delhi University Keynote Speaker April 2019 - April 2019 (1 month) New Delhi Area, India

Demystifying the Artificial Intelligence Landscape

Rotaract District 3011
Keynote Speaker & Member - Panel discussion
March 2019 - March 2019 (1 month)
New Delhi Area, India

Journey to Success: Problem Solving, Planning & Organising (21st Century Employability Skills)

Entrepreneurship Cell, IIT Kharagpur Mentor November 2018 - March 2019 (5 months) New Delhi Area, India

Is part of the Mentor pool for Empresario 2018-2019. Helping StartUps with their business plans and strategy. Mentoring them in creating a feasible and market-ready Business Model for the idea, supported by strong customer validation.

Entrepreneurship Cell, IIM Rohtak Mentor November 2018 - February 2019 (4 months) New Delhi Area, India

Helping StartUps with their business plan and strategy. Assessing the MVP / Prototype and recommending changes required to make it market ready. Mentoring them in creating a feasible and market-ready Business Model for the idea, supported by strong customer validation.

How Achievers Think
CEO | Curator
February 2018 - February 2019 (1 year 1 month)
Page 4 of 6

New Delhi Area, India

Responsible for assembling, cataloguing, managing and presenting blogs for How Achievers Think.

TED Conferences Speaker January 2019 - January 2019 (1 month) Balajii ITS

The power of sharing Ideas.

Doing your own thing is tough and every country sees more failures than success. Culturally we are not groomed to fail and failure is frowned upon. Life thrives on celebrations and a society that fails to appreciate failures stifles innovation and creativity even before it can start. A person failing has to be OK as failures often teach an individual, what to do and what not to do.

Shiv Nadar University
Jury Member - SNU AIC
December 2018 - January 2019 (2 months)
Noida Area, India

International Initiative for Impact Evaluation (3ie)
Human resource officer
November 2014 - January 2019 (4 years 3 months)
New Delhi

Global Development Network 4 years HR & Administrative - Assistant 2010 - 2014 (4 years)

HR & Administrative - Associate 2010 - 2012 (2 years)

## Education

Wharton Online
Entrepreneurship Specialization · (2019 - 2020)

NIMS - National Institute Of Management Solutions Master of Business Administration - MBA, Human Resources Development · (2007 - 2008)

Delhi University
Bachelor's degree, Statistics · (2002 - 2005)

St. Xavier School, Hazaribagh
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Mathematics · (1988 - 2000)